A romance of Scotland Yard
Blackmail is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Alfred Hitchcock.
London, 1929.
Frank Webber, a very busy Scotland Yard detective, seems to be more
interested in his work than in Alice White, his girlfriend.
Feeling herself ignored, Alice agrees to go out with an elegant and
well-mannered artist who invites her to visit his fancy apartment.
Alice White, played by Anny Ondra.
Mrs. White, played by Sara Allgood.
Mr. White, played by Charles Paton.
Detective Frank Webber, played by John Longden.
Tracy, played by Donald Calthrop.
The Artist, played by Cyril Ritchard.
Blackmail is a 1929 British crime thriller film directed by Alfred Hitchcock
and starring Anny Ondra, John Longden, and Cyril Ritchard.
Based on the 1928 play of the same name by Charles Bennett, the film is about a London
woman who is blackmailed after killing a man who tries to rape her.
After starting production as a silent film, British International
Pictures decided to adapt Blackmail into a separate sound film.
It became the first successful European talkie; a silent version was released for cinemas not equipped
for sound (at 6,740 feet), with the sound version (7,136 feet) released at the same time.
Both versions are held in the British Film Institute collection.
Blackmail is frequently cited as the first British sound feature film.
It was voted the best British film of 1929 in a
UK poll the year it was released.
In 2017 a poll of 150 actors, directors, writers, producers and critics for Time
Out magazine ranked Blackmail as the 59th best British film ever.
On 1 January 2025, the film's copyright expired in the
United States, and is now in the public domain.
The film explores themes of london, england, blackmail, scotland
yard, based on play or musical, black and white.
The tone is emotional and intense.